Finding aid for Department of Afroamerican and African Studies (University of Michigan) records, 1966-2010 (bulk 1970-1994)
Bentley Historical Library
- Audio recordings on cassettes, 1975-2001
  - Robert Hayden Memorial
    - John Hatcher, Melba Boyd, Alan Wald & Lemuel Johnson: The tension between belief and ideology in the work of Robert Hayden, 1990 February 24; audiocassette; (10am Tape 1; John Hatcher, Melba Boyd, Alan Wald & Lemuel Johnson speaking on the subject of "The tension between belief and ideology in the work of Robert Hayden.") (Box 31)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-230-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-230-2]
    - John Hatcher, Melba Boyd, Alan Wald & Lemuel Johnson: The tension between belief and ideology in the work of Robert Hayden, 1990 February 24; audiocassette; (10am Tape 2; John Hatcher, Melba Boyd, Alan Wald & Lemuel Johnson speaking on the subject of "The tension between belief and ideology in the work of Robert Hayden.") (Box 31)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-231-1]
    - Sherley Anne Williams: Poetry reading, 1990 February 24; audiocassette; (1pm; Sherley Anne Williams speaking on Robert Hayden at the tribute to his life and poetry.) (Box 31)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-232-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-232-2]
    - John W. Aldridge, Alvin Aubert, Melba Boyd, Gwendolyn Brooks, Michael S. Harper, John Hatcher, Pinkie Gordon Lane, Naomi Long Madgett, Dudley Randall, Eugene Redmond, Ronald Scott: Poems, memories and testimonials, 1990 February 24; audiocassette; (2pm Tape 1; John W. Aldridge, Alvin Aubert, Melba Boyd, Gwendolyn Brooks, Michael S. Harper, John Hatcher, Pinkie Gordon Lane, Naomi Long Madgett, Dudley Randall, Eugene Redmond, Ronald Scott: Poems, memories and testimonials) (Box 31)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-233-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-233-2]
    - John W. Aldridge, Alvin Aubert, Melba Boyd, Gwendolyn Brooks, Michael S. Harper, John Hatcher, Pinkie Gordon Lane, Naomi Long Madgett, Dudley Randall, Eugene Redmond, Ronald Scott: Poems, memories and testimonials, 1990 February 24; audiocassette; (2pm Tape 2; John W. Aldridge, Alvin Aubert, Melba Boyd, Gwendolyn Brooks, Michael S. Harper, John Hatcher, Pinkie Gordon Lane, Naomi Long Madgett, Dudley Randall, Eugene Redmond, Ronald Scott: Poems, memories and testimonials) (Box 31)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-234-1]
    - Rita Dove: Poetry reading, 1990 February 24; audiocassette; (4pm; Rita Dove speaking on Robert Hayden at his memorial and tribute to his poetry.) (Box 31)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-235-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-235-2]
  - Workshop on Strengthening CAAS and Africana Studies at U-M
    - Evelyn Barbee and Lemuel Johnson: Introduction, Q&A, 1989 April 25; audiocassette; (Tape 1; Introduction by Evelyn Barbee and Question and Answer Session led by Lemuel Johnson. The Campus Inn 615 East Huron St, Ann Arbor, MI) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-236-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-236-2]
    - Walter Allen and Nesha Haniff: Ford Foundation grant / proposal and what it means to the Center's future, 1989 April 25; audiocassette; (Tape 2; Workshop I Continued; Dr. Walter Allen & Nesha Haniff; Ford Foundation Grant and Proposal and What It Means to the Center's Future. The Campus Inn615 East Huron St, Ann Arbor, MI.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-237-1]
    - Walter Allen and Nesha Haniff: Ford Foundation grant / proposal and what it means to the Center's future, 1989 April 25; audiocassette; (Tape 3; Dr. Walter Allen & Nesha Haniff; Ford Foundation Grant and Proposal and What It Means to the Center's Future. The Campus Inn, 615 East Huron St, Ann Arbor, MI) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-238-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-238-2]
    - Administrative issues in seeking departmental issues, circa 1989 April 24; audiocassette; (Tape 4; Workshop on Administrative Issues in Seeking Departmental Issues. The Campus Inn, 615 East Huron St, Ann Arbor, MI.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-239-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-239-2]
    - Governance with fewer faculty, circa 1989 April 24; audiocassette; (Tape 5; Workshop on Governance with Fewer Faculty at CAAS. The Campus Inn, 615 East Huron St, Ann Arbor, MI.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-240-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-240-2]
    - Long-range goals of CAAS, circa 1989 April 24; audiocassette; (Tape 6; Workshop on Long-range goals of CAAS. The Campus Inn, 615 East Huron St, Ann Arbor, MI.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-241-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-241-2]
    - Role of the CAAS library, circa 1989 April 24; audiocassette; (Tape 7; Workshop on the Role of the CAAS Library. The Campus Inn, 615 East Huron St, Ann Arbor, MI.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-242-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-242-2]
    - Role of the CAAS library, circa 1989 April 24; audiocassette; (Tape 8; Workshop on the Role of the CAAS Library. The Campus Inn, 615 East Huron St, Ann Arbor, MI.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-243-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-243-2]
  - CAAS Symposium for Black History Month: Black American Families
    - Fred McCuiston, Larry Fox, William Ratcliff and Michael Cross: Young, Black, and Male in America: An Endangered Species, 1991 February 14; audiocassette; (Tape 1 of 2; Honigman Auditorium, 100 Hutchins Hall, Law Quad. A Discussion with; Fred McCuiston, Ann Arbor Chapter, NAACP; Larry Fox, Community Organizer, Ann Arbor; William Ratcliff, Director, Saturday Academy for African American Students; Michael Cross, Director, Male Responsiblity Program, Detroit Urban League; Sponsored by the Center for Afroamerican and African Studies; The School of Social Work; The Department of Psychology; The Women's Studies Program) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-244-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-244-2]
    - Fred McCuiston, Larry Fox, William Ratcliff and Michael Cross: Young, Black, and Male in America: An Endangered Species, 1991 February 14; audiocassette; (Tape 2 of 2; Honigman Auditorium, 100 Hutchins Hall, Law Quad. A Discussion with; Fred McCuiston, Ann Arbor Chapter, NAACP; Larry Fox, Community Organizer, Ann Arbor; William Ratcliff, Director, Saturday Academy for African American Students; Michael Cross, Director, Male Responsiblity Program, Detroit Urban League; Sponsored by the Center for Afroamerican and African Studies; The School of Social Work; The Department of Psychology; The Women's Studies Program) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-245-1]
    - Earl Lewis, DeWitt S. Dykes, Jr. and Robert J. Taylor: Black Families: A Status Report, 1991 February 15; audiocassette; (Tape 1 of 4; 10:00-10:30 Welcome by Earl Lewis, Associate Professor of History and Afroamerican and African Studies and Interim Director, Center for Afroamerican and African Studies; Opening remarks by Vonnie C. McLoyd, Associate Professor Psychology and Associate Research Scientist, Center for Human Growth and Development; 10:30-12:00 Panel 1. "Black Families: A Status Report"' Moderator: Early Lewis, Associate Professor of History and Afroamerican and African Studies and Interim Director, CAAS; De Witt S. Dykes, Jr., Professor of History Oakland University; "Modern Black Families in Historical Perspective"; Robert J. Taylor, Associate Professor of Social Work; "The State of Black American Families, 1980-1990".) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-246-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-246-2]
    - Vonnie C. McLoyd, Susan Frazier-Kouassi and Philip Bowman: Mothers, Fathers, Grandparents, 1991 February 15; audiocassette; (Tape 2 of 4; 1:30-3:00 Panel 2. "Mothers, Fathers, Grandparents"; Moderator: Vonnie C. McLoyd, Associate Professor of Psychology and Associate Research Scientist, Center for Human Growth and Development;Susan Frazier-Kouassi, Lecturer, Women's Studies and Afroamerican and African Studies; "The Psychological Well-Being of Black Single Parent Women"; Philip Bowman, Associate Professor of Educational Policy Studies, Afro-American Studies, and Psychology, University of Illinois, Urbana; "Black Fathers: Research Issues and Challenges for the 21st Century.") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-247-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-247-2]
    - Andrea G. Hunter, Oscar Barbarin III and Toni C. Antonucci: Hunter: Mothers, Fathers, Grandparents; Barbarin & Antonucci: Families Coping with Stress, 1991 February 15; audiocassette; (Tape 3 of 4; Continued from Tape 2, Andrea G. Hunter, Research Assistant Professor of Psychology and Black Studies, University of Pittsburgh; "Black Grandmothers in Multigenerational Households: Adaptive Strategies for Parenting Support"; 3:00-3:15 Coffee and tea break, Rackham Assembly Hall; 3:15-4:45 Panel 3 "Families Coping With Stress; Oscar A. Barbarin, III, Associate Professor of Social Work"Resilience in African American Families Distressed by Illness and Poverty"; Toni C. Antonucci, Associate Professor of Human Development Psychology; "Intergenerational Family Relations") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-248-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-248-2]
    - James S. Jackson: Families Coping with Stress, 1991 February 15; audiocassette; (Tape 4 of 4; James S. Jackson, Professor of Psychology "Family Structure, Work, and Stress.") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-249-1]
    - Vycki Johnson: Workshop: Black Youths, 1991 February 16; audiocassette; (Workshop 2. Rackham West Conference Room - Facilitators: Andrea G. Hunter, Research Assistant Professor of Psychology and Black Studies, University of Pittsburgh; and Henry V. Davis, Assistant Professor of History, Western Michigan University; "Afro-American Men's Views of Male Family Roles") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-250-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-250-2]
    - Andrea G. Hunter and Henry Davis: Workshop: Afro-American Men's Views of Male Family Roles, 1991 February 16; audiocassette; (10:30-10:45 Coffee break, East and West Conference Rooms; 10:45-12:15 Workshop 3. Rackham East Conference Room, Facilitator: Susan Frazier-Kouassi, Lecturer in Women's Studies and Afroamerican and African Studies; "Black Single Parent Women: Future Directions.") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-251-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-251-2]
    - Susan Frazier-Kouassi: Workshop: Black, Single Parent Women: Future Directions, 1991 February 16; audiocassette; (Facilitator: Vycki Johnson, M.S. G.S.W., Family Worker, Boysville of Michigan.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-252-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-252-2]
    - DeWitt S. Dykes, Jr.: Workshop: Methods for tracing Black Family Genealogy, 1991 February 16; audiocassette; (9:00-10:30 Workshop 1. Rackham East Conference Room; Facilitator: Dewitt S. Dykes Jr., Professor of History, Oakland University.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-253-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-253-2]
  - Inventions of Africa: Africa in the Literatures of the Continent and the Diaspora Workshops
    - Maxwell Owusu, E. Nii Quarcoopome and Lorna McDaniel: Workshop 1: African Voices: Literature in Context, 1991 October 23; audiocassette; (Tape 1; Maxwell Owusu - Professor of Anthropology "Ethnography of Africa: The Usefulness of the Useless" Revisited; E. Nii Quarcoopome - Assistant Professor of Afroamerican and African Studies and History of Art "The Fountain of Knowledge: Language Aesthetics Political Ideology in Ga-Dangme Society; Lorna McDaniel, Associtate Professor of Ethnomusicology - Gifts of Power; First in a series of workshops to explore common dimensions of the literatures of an African diaspora.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-254-1]
    - Maxwell Owusu, E. Nii Quarcoopome and Lorna McDaniel: Workshop 1: African Voices: Literature in Context, 1991 October 23; audiocassette; (Tape 2; Maxwell Owusu - Professor of Anthropology "Ethnography of Africa: The Usefulness of the Useless" Revisited; E. Nii Quarcoopome - Assistant Professor of Afroamerican and African Studies and History of Art "The Fountain of Knowledge: Language Aesthetics Political Ideology in Ga-Dangme Society; Lorna McDaniel, Associtate Professor of Ethnomusicology - Gifts of Power; First in a series of workshops to explore common dimensions of the literatures of an African diaspora) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-255-1]
    - Abena Busia: Workshop 3: The Construction of the Absence of Black Women in the Discourse, 1992 February 04; audiocassette; (Abena Busia, Professor of English, Rutgers University officiating workshop.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-257-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-257-2]
    - Inventions of Africa: Africa in the Literatures of the Continent and the Diaspora Workshops; Daryl Cumber Dance: "I Put the Tail Back Where I Find it", 1991 November 15; audiocassette; (Recording unintelligible. Program recorded at very low level and contains loud background noise. High amount of hiss & hum on tape.] Daryl Cumber Dance, Professor of English - Virginia Commonwealth University and author of "Shuckin' and Jivin': Folklore from Contemporary Black Americans and Folklore from Contemporary Jamaicans")
      - [Side 1; no Side 2], [2012140-SR-256-1]
  - CAAS 20th Anniversary
    - Charles D. Moody: Opening Remarks, 1991 March 15; audiocassette; (Tape 1; Charles D. Moody, VP for Minority Affairs giving opening remarks for the CAAS 20th Anniversary.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-259-1]
    - Keynote address: Establishing New Paradigms: The Creation & Growth of Africana Studies, 1991 March 15; audiocassette; (Tape 2; Keynote address; "Establishing New Paradigms: The Creation & Growth of Africana Studies") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-260-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-260-2]
    - Panel: From BAM to CAAS "Origins and Aims of CAAS", 1991 March 15; audiocassette; (Tape 3; Panel 1; From BAM to CAAS "Origins and Aims of CAAS") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-261-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-261-2]
    - Panel: From BAM to CAAS "Origins and Aims of CAAS", 1991 March 15; audiocassette; (Tape 3a; Fri. Day 1: Panel 1 continued. From BAM to CAAS "Origins and Aims of CAAS.") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-262-1]
    - Panel: Models for African Studies, 1991 March 15; audiocassette; (Tape 4; Fri. Day1: Panel 2; "Models for African Studies.") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-263-1]
    - Panel: Models for African Studies, 1991 March 15; audiocassette; (Tape 4a; Day 1 Fri: 3/15/91 Moderator: Ronald Woods, "Models for African Studies.") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-264-1]
    - Panel: New Curriculum Options, 1991 March 15; audiocassette; (Tape 5; Panel 3 entitled "New Curriculum Options.") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-265-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-265-2]
    - Awards, 1991 March 15; audiocassette; (Day 1; Tape 6; Awards ceremony presented at the 20th anniversary of CAAS.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-266-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-266-2]
    - Emery Smith, Roderick Linzie, Stephanie Johnson, Devlin Ponte and Abdul Goler: Workshop: The Next Generation of Scholars: Towards a Student-centered Academy, 1991 March 16; audiocassette; (Tape1; Day 2; Panel discussion, Moderator - Emery Smith; Panelists: Roderick Linzie, Stephanie Johnson, Devlin Ponte, Abdul Goler.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-267-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-267-2]
    - Emery Smith, Roderick Linzie, Stephanie Johnson, Devlin Ponte and Abdul Goler: Workshop: The Next Generation of Scholars: Towards a Student-centered Academy, 1991 March 16; audiocassette; (General audience and Panelists commentary.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-268-1]
    - Tracye Matthews, Brenda Flanagan, Jan Collins-Eaglin and Linda Chatters: Workshop: The Dynamics of Gender in Africana Studies and the Academy, 1991 March 16; audiocassette; (Tape 2; Moderator: Tracey Matthew; Panelists: Brenda Flanagan, Jan Collins-Eaglin, Linda Chatters.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-269-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-269-2]
    - Tracye Matthews, Brenda Flanagan, Jan Collins-Eaglin and Linda Chatters: Workshop: The Dynamics of Gender in Africana Studies and the Academy, 1991 March 16; audiocassette; (Tape 2A; General Audience and Panelist commentary) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-270-1]
    - J. Frank Yates: Closing: Challenges for Future Development, 1991 March 16; audiocassette; (Tape 3; J. Frank Yates: Closing Session; "Challenges for Future Development") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-271-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-271-2]
  - Race, Culture and the Politics of Intellectual Inquiry Lecture Series
    - Patricia Williams: Equality's Demise and the Problem of Black Identity, 1991 November 04; audiocassette; (The 2nd lecture of 7 in Race, Culture and the Politics of Intellectual Inquiry Lecture Series. Patricia Williams, Professor of Law; University of Wisconsin at Madison.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-272-1]
    - Manning Marable: Of Our Spiritual Strivings: Black America Searches for Itself, 1992 January 10; audiocassette; (The 4th lecture of 7 in Race, Culture and the Politics of Intellectual Inquiry Lecture Series. Dr. Manning Marable is currently Professor of Political Science, History and Sociology at the University of Colorado, Boulder and is also affiliated with the Center for Studies of Ethnicity and Race in America.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-274-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-274-2]
    - Evelyn Brooks Higginbotham: Race, History and Feminist Theory, 1992 February 14; audiocassette; (The 5th lecture of 7 in Race, Culture and the Politics of Intellectual Inquiry Lecture Series. Evelyn Brooks Higginbotham - Professor of History, University of Pennsylvania, [...]author of African-American Women's History and the Metalanguage of Race.") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-275-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-275-2]
    - George Lipsitz: As Nasty as They Wanna Be: Racial Politics and Intellectual Inquiry, 1991 March 13; audiocassette; (The 6th lecture of 7 in Race, Culture and the Politics of Intellectual Inquiry Lecture Series. George Lipsitz: Professor of Ethnic Studies, University of California, San Diego; Professor Lipsitz is the author of "Time Passages, Collective Memory and American Popular Culture.") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-276-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-276-2]
    - K. Anthony Appiah: Ancestral Voices: The Case for an African American Philosophy, 1992 April 03; audiocassette; (Tape 1; The 7th lecture of 7 in Race, Culture and the Politics of Intellectual Inquiry Lecture Series. A year-long project to elaborate and expand upon the question of how issues of "race" and culture have been shaped by the politics of intellectual inquiry in the United States. K. Anthony Appiah, Associate Professor, Department of African American Studies, Harvard University and author of the book "In My Father's House: Africa in the Philosophy of Culture") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-277-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-277-2]
    - K. Anthony Appiah: Ancestral Voices: The Case for an African American Philosophy, 1992 April 03; audiocassette; (Tape 2; The 7th lecture of 7 in Race, Culture and the Politics of Intellectual Inquiry Lecture Series. A year-long project to elaborate and expand upon the question of how issues of "race" and culture have been shaped by the politics of intellectual inquiry in the United States. K. Anthony Appiah, Associate Professor, Department of African American Studies, Harvard University and author of the book "In My Father's House: Africa in the Philosophy of Culture") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-278-1]
  - Remapping of Scholarship: African peoples in the Industrial Age
    - Michael Awkward, Earl Lewis, John Higginson, Tyler Stovall, Joe Trotter: Opening, 1994 September 30; audiocassette; (Tape 1; Opening: Michael Awkward; Intro: Earl Lewis. Speakers: John Higginson, Tyler Stoval, Joe Trotter.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-279-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-279-2]
    - Joe Trotter, Keletso Atkins and Tiffany Patterson: Panel 1, 1994 September 30; audiocassette; (Tape 2; Panel 1; Open Discussion on part 1. Speakers are Joe Trotter, Keletso Atkins and Tiffany Patterson.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-280-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-280-2]
    - Open discussion: Open discussion, 1994 September 30; audiocassette; (Tape 3; Discussion Part #2 Continuation of the Race, Culture, and the Politics of Intellectual Inquiry Lecture series.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-281-1]
    - Nahun Chandler, Antonio Sergio, Alfredo Guimaraes and Denise Hood: Panel 2: Social and Political Identities, 1994 October 01; audiocassette; (Tape 4; Panel 2; Nahun Chandler, Antonio Sergio, Alfredo Guimaraes and Denise Hood: "Social and Political Identities.") (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-282-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-282-2]
    - Hanes Walton, B. Nantang Jua: Comments, 1994 October 01; audiocassette; (Tape 5; Hanes Walton, B. Nantang Jua: Comments from the audience as well.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-283-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-283-2]
    - Carolyn Cooper, Abiola Irele, 1994 October 01; audiocassette; (Tape 6; Speakers are Carolyn Cooper and Abiola Irele.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-284-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-284-2]
  - Graduate Student Conference [became Student of Color of Rackham (SCOR]
    - Dean John D'Arms, Todd Shaw, Cheedy Jaja, Bilinda Straight, Lemuel Johnson: Session 1: Frameworks for Afro-American and African Studies, 1991 February 01; audiocassette; (Tape 1; Opening Remarks - Dean John D'Arms, Horace H. Rackham Graduate School. Assistant Dean James Jackson, University of Michigan, Horace H. Rackham Graduate School. Session I - West Conference Room. Frameworks for Afroamerican and African Studies. Presenters: Todd Shaw, Political Science"Context and Character: A Theoretical Framework for Examining Black Leadership and Black Mass Principles." Cheedy Jaja, Bowling Green State University "Philosophy and Culture Possiblities for an African Philosophy". Bilinda Straight, Anthropology "Sub-Saharan African Religion, Indigenous vs. Imperial Power." Discussants - Professor Lemuel Johnson, CAAS, English.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-285-1]
      - [side 2], [2012140-SR-285-2]
    - Dean John D'Arms, Todd Shaw, Cheedy Jaja, Bilinda Straight, Lemuel Johnson: Session 1: Frameworks for Afro-American and African Studies, 1991 February 01; audiocassette; (Recording unintelligible. Program recorded at very low level and contains loud background noise.] Tape 2; Opening Remarks - Dean John D'Arms, Horace H. Rackham Graduate School; Assistant Dean James Jackson, University of Michigan, Horace H. Rackham Graduate School; Session I - West Conference RoomFrameworks for Afroamerican and African Studies; Presenters: Todd Shaw, Political Science; "Context and Character: A Theoretical Framework for Examining Black Leadership and Black Mass Principles"; Cheedy Jaja, Bowling Green State University "Philosophy and Culture Possiblities for an African Philosophy"; Bilinda Straight, Anthropology "Sub-Saharan African Religion, Indigenous vs. Imperial Power"; Discussants - Professor Lemuel Johnson, CAAS, English.) (Box 32)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-286-1]
    - Otto Gonzalez, John Stiles, Gracia Clark & Keletso Atkins: Session 2A: To Be a Colonial: Life in a Colonial and Post-Colonial World, 1991 February 02; audiocassette; (Tape 1; Session 2A; To Be A Colonial, Life in a Colonial and Post-Colonial World; Presenters: Otto Gonzalez, Natural Resources; "Third World Threatened by a New World in 1992"; John Stiles, Anthropology; "Revolutionary Logic, Republican Myth, Politics, Culture and Assimilation in the Departmentalization of the French Antilles"; Discussants, Assistant Professor Garcia Clark, CAAS, Anthropology; Assistant Professor Kelesto Atkins, CAAS, History) (Box 32)